What's your name, Howard?
What's your name?
McCawdore, the Mama Special Utility Authority Board Meeting.
For Monday, May 23, 2022.
To the five United States and America, and the two of the Republic for which it stands.
One nation, another god, and the divisible of the liberty and justice for all.
This meeting will now be contained through the Council Chamber's Reconvening and the staff room
of the executive session.
I'll move to number six.
Resolution 2022, that's year or two.
And I believe we're going to have some questions for Miss Vance.
So, you can go to the podium.
So, we have discussion upstairs in the executive session.
We talked about what we think we're going to do.
But we wanted to ask you some questions.
I don't know who else to go first.
You have your questions in there.
May?
Yes.
Did you have any kind of presentation, anything?
Did you want to give us?
What presentation?
Okay.
Go ahead and I'll give us a chance to.
So, I will say this conversation has been many years coming for us for super excited about this project.
But our plan is to, you know, we're the board store.
You know, the board store currently is that we're going to go to state of the art,
Chrysler facility.
And we're going to use their image program, which is not something that we've done in the past.
So, it'll be, it'll be cutting edge.
Probably how to set the separate Jeep sharing as well.
So, really as soon as we get approval for this, that's our next call.
This to them and they'll help us design that facility.
And then, where the VFW used to stand, we are planning to build a commercial shop there.
That will be able to, you know, work on all the brands that we sell, so, for GM and RAM as well.
And then, like, we've been talking about.
And we just kind of see where it goes from there.
Or we're really the fact that we have these three stores here in Miami now.
Probably we'll open up some other possibilities for us much like it doesn't get through.
We have a lot of other niche businesses that we run there.
So, I can see that coming this way in the future.
Thank you guys.
Sure.
You guys.
I know John is doing you guys on the warehouse.
We're doing different warehouses.
Yeah.
For sure.
He did just purchase somewhere else.
He does a lot of different side businesses and stuff like that, as they make sense in the communities.
So, just excited to work with the city of Miami.
Thank you guys for really progressive and a lot of the things that you're all we're doing right now.
We'd love to be a part of helping, you know, to find a main street.
And I think this would be a really, really good step in the right direction.
The question I had was a 30 employees is that doable. I mean, I know Guthrie has a lot of employees
You guys got like I've been to your Guthrie store picking up police cars and stuff like that is that like 40 or 50 employees
That there's a correct oh in in Guthrie
Over 100 okay
I mean employees do you have your current store crasher at the price you're struggling with 22 full-time okay
So 30 is very doable. I thought it was fair. I thought it was doable
I'll tell you when we did the numbers. I was trying to be conservative so that we could exceed
Those numbers, but yeah, I mean with technicians things alone. I think that's the reason
So there's the reason that becomes a discussion obviously making it is these guys are having to justify
The expense that the city is is trying to invest in this project and jobs is this one of the biggest drivers
To city so that was part of that conversation is justified what number of jobs?
Are they new jobs? Are they just moving the jobs they have and so so that being additional age jobs?
It's what it would be a pretty good average looking at the medium income
You're in the city
So you're saying that you're gonna have a
Crystall store and a Jeep store
That is the that is the idea and now we have available to start on the our image project yet because
If this part done first, but yes, very likely that
So you guys have a Jeep event
Guthrie there
So yes, so we do a festival in Guthrie. It's the first one
That we've ever done
This is our fourth annual
It's called midwest jeep fast
We did that to raise awareness for really we had a hard time getting people to realize get three wasn't so far away
Right, so right outside of a metro area
So it was to get people to drive and then also to is a charitable event
So I mean if I had my way everything we do I wouldn't do any regular advertising and we're getting closer to this
It would be you know supporting community stuff and taking good care of our customers
So they come back to see if that's our vision and for the way to draw business and so we started that festival
We have we've raised anywhere between 10 to 15 thousand dollars. We just finished it again
We donate to causes like the girl wise veteran of America was last year
This camping that we're just finishing afterwards for make promises happen, which is
Organization that helps and individuals with
Disabilities so we take a different charity every year and we have a Jeep track bill
And it tracks it tracks quite a few people. I mean thousands of people come to turn up that so that's pretty good
So we started off in Maine and then COVID got weird so we tried it
So we're kind of trying to figure out exactly
When the right time to do that is that it ideally may like
the first or second weekend in May is when we have most of our customers.
Would you be interested in doing a fall event here?
Possibly.
Absolutely.
I want to do accept like that.
Maybe a spring went out there and a fall in here.
That could definitely be a month later.
Most of us are.
Most of us are partners.
Yeah.
Well, the brings people.
You have to do a simple step here.
And that's really where the city of Guthrie started doing.
We supported from the very beginning.
Nice started in music.
That's what was called make that we're, so we supported that.
That's turned into bread, bread, bread, nights for the city of Guthrie.
And it's a huge draw and we'd love being involved with things like that and I see you all doing
a lot of that.
It's like when you can just put our heads together and a bright storm on different events,
that's a really cool thing to come out of that, so definitely open it as part of it.
So here's a weird question.
Have you ever heard of an entirely electric facility for one of these?
So, no, I haven't.
I have somebody hitting me up about using a solar, but I haven't had a presentation from them.
But other than that, I don't know much about that.
Well, electric cars, yes, total electric facilities.
It's the, it's the municipal electric provider that we are.
Yeah.
The electric is good.
Helps off set or investment?
For sure.
So, it's why we asked, we didn't know if that was something that's either possible or something.
I don't.
Not that I know of.
It's not something we're looking at and I'll tell you with all of these EVs and such.
You can guarantee we'll be drawing our fair share of electricity.
So with the total investment that you'll be making into that property with the purchase
of the property and the buildings and everything where you look for that to be.
Just for the Chrysler project.
Yes.
That's what we kind of tell the charging stations available.
You know, we haven't quite figured that something we're doing some research on to try to figure
that out now how we do this.
I just came back from meeting in Vegas.
We were talking about, so we're wrapping our minds around that, how we do public charging.
So, we're still figuring that piece out, but possibly yes, it makes sense for us to do that.
There's not a lot of charging stations and trying to help with the infrastructure.
We certainly know the sales of EV vehicles in this community if we need more.
Absolutely.
Our manufacturer is also, well, say, GM specifically, because I just came back from that meeting
or asking us to give feedback on places where we think there's a need for that.
So, scouting out some areas where they're sparse.
So, I'm actually getting ready.
My husband is getting ready to have an electric truck so we can kind of dabble in this and
see what this looks like.
I want to take a very trip and you see from the consumer's office, what's going on so we can get
some feedback on that.
So, when I asked the question about the investment, you said, in the Chrysler piece, so is there
a Ford piece, too?
Right.
So, the plan is, while we have the construction have any here, it's to do it based on the Ford
store as well.
Look at some things.
What kind of investment would that be?
You know, I don't know the numbers on that.
It would be substantial, but I don't know the numbers on that yet.
We're going to tell you about lighting, yeah, the lighting,
the main stream of both sides, the four-store and with the going theme
with the rest of the lighting, we have all the main stream.
Telling you, I want to talk to that,
since you're the smart one.
We talked about the new lighting, the mass downtown,
and what you also do that at it.
It's a resolution on the proof, we also have that you would do that
on the other side, the other side, the other side, the other side.
So it would be the mass, so we can...
Yeah, I'm sure that I'm sure that would be the one.
We want to be good stewards of the community,
and do what we need to do to make it work for the price of the bank, not only.
If everything was to happen, when would be a projected date to start construction?
Well, if this is approved, I literally, the day after this is approved,
I'm going to put our deposit down with Chrysler,
and they'll start their image program.
We've already talked across the construction.
It will be using there, so I mean, I think it would go pretty quickly.
I mean, surely, I would think within six months, we'd be started.
Maybe sooner I can retain.
Really, just as soon as possible, we're ready to pull the trigger and get going.
Our employees are so excited for the possibility of this happening.
We've been telling them, since we purchased that Chrysler short of it.
We wanted to do something like this, so we would not hesitate.
It would not be on our end.
It's a good one.
So the cost of construction would do the whole project.
I believe so.
Yes, that's what he's been speaking to.
I believe that's, but I don't know how the final is on that yet.
So, if we give both the permission to negotiate,
then we talked about doing a meeting maybe Friday,
if he came back with something.
Would that be okay?
Sure.
I mean, we would want to know what it would.
What would we do with the closing instead?
What?
We're wanting to have a meeting on our next schedule council meeting to approve it.
We're not to approve it.
Which would be June 6th.
June 6th.
So is it?
Do you need a move faster than that?
Well, I mean, the faster the better for us, like I said, we've been waiting to just pull the trigger
with Chrysler.
I mean, you know, whatever we need to do.
to make it work for everybody here.
But that doesn't cause any problems with your negotiation with the seller.
That part, I don't know what his time frame is.
I can tell you, you need to expect that today we're going to know one way or another.
I don't know. I can't really speak to that.
I don't have to ask him if there's a time frame on that.
I don't need to know.
Did you have a closing date already?
Did you expect him to sign or be the closing?
I don't know the date.
I just knew this is the one thing we were away.
So Friday meeting?
Friday lunch?
Make her all sandwiches?
I'll buy lunch.
Probably not.
I already have our hesitations that I can speak to.
Nope, I think what can I explain a little bit about?
I'll give him the depth of the discussion and numbers that were discussed.
They came up with some numbers that they wanted me to meet with.
The buyer in the seller and find two of those numbers.
The city had an exact number of what was necessary for this to get done.
because they're going to be putting those numbers into an actual public resolution.
That will have to be voted on and approved.
So that was why they today are in a position where they can grant
maybe authority a city manager to meet with the fire and seller
and finalize those numbers and then they can give it
drawn up into a resolution, we call it meeting,
meeting it would be a special meeting that we would have to file.
Can we get it Friday, that would still give you the 31st date.
Sure.
Yeah, I'll make that work.
Okay, we're going to the Friday, going to the Friday.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it Friday.
So we need to make it.
We might have been in hell.
You say that three times.
Why are you going to be like that?
I just...
I don't know what we're doing.
be driving the school with us and I guess with the emotion, I'll make the motion.
What motion is it?
You're going to, you by the motion.
No, I'll second your motion.
What motion was it?
The city manager leaves on.
Right.
There you go.
Do we need to officially say that?
So I'll make the motion that we authorize both receding manager to negotiate and deal with the
buyer and seller and then come back and have a final meeting to,
do I have to say all that within the terms within the terms of discussed in executive
session?
I don't know.
Second.
Thank you.
Yes.
It's a mouthful.
All right.
So full.
Senator.
Davis.
I'm staying.
Parker.
All right.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Number seven.
A German.
So moved.
Thank you.